Guide to the Center for International Studies records, 1960-1983.
Center for International Studies records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Center for International Studies records, 1960-1983.
53-5-2158
Cornell University Center for International Studies.
29 cubic ft.
Correspondence, printed materials, publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Departmental files include material concerning course offerings and conferences; fellowships, grants and funding sources; department and director's correspondence;
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Departmental files include material concerning course offerings and conferences; fellowships, grants and funding sources; department and director's correspondence; and records of the European Studies Program. Also, correspondence files; files of Prof. Richard N. Rosecrance; and accounts files.
Records of of the Air War in Indochina Study Group, conducted by Raphael Littauer and Norman Uphoff, which led to the publication of The Air War in Indochina, with an introduction by Neil Sheehan, 1972
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University; Littauer, Raphael, 1925-; Rosecrance, Richard N.; Uphoff, Norman Thomas.; Cornell University. Air War Study Group.
Subjects:
International relations -- Study and teaching.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Aerial operations, American.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
See also the Center for International Studies Research Material, #53-5-1606 and the Ford Foundation Proposal, #53-5-1533.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Financial Documents
Series II. Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory
Series III. CIS and Related Publications
"The Air War In Indochina"
Series IV. Fellowships, Grants, Foundations and Institutions
ESC - Ford
Fulbright Hays
Series V. Faculty and Visitor Related Documents
Irwin T. Sanders Evaluations
Series VI. CIS Committees and Affairs
International Population Program
Series VII. Departmental Affairs
Series VIII. Proposals and Proposal Materials
Series IX. Education Documents
National Defense of Education Act
Series X. International Involvement and Affairs
International Law
Institute of European Studies
World Food
Vietnam and Indochina
China and Japan
Series XI. Wider Cornell University Committees and Affairs
Campus Unrest, 1969
Course Descriptions
Budget Strife
Board of Trustees
International Studies Major
Series XII. Publications
Series XIII. Assorted Documents
Appendix III
Series XIV. Correspondence
Series XV. Research, Articles, and Presentations
Articles Concerning Race Relations
Articles Concerning India
Articles Concerning Agriculture
Series XVI. Peace Studies
Series XVII. Western Societies Program
Papers for Publication
Sidney Tarrow
Series XVIII. Overarching CIS Chronology
Series XIX. Agricultural Institutes
Series XX. Library Resources for Courses
Series XXI. Audio
Carpenter Lectures
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Financial Documents
  - CIS - Budget Review Committee Documents, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - CIS - Ten Year Projection, 1966-1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - CIS - Monthly Expenditure Reports, July 1967-June 1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Assorted CIS Administrative and Financial Documents, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - CIS - Financial Reports, Mainly Monthly, August 1967-May 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - CIS - Tuition Payment Documents, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - CIS - Financial Reports, February 1968-August 1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Assorted CIS Administrative and Financial Documents, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - CIS -Monthly Financial Report, February 1969-March 1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - CIS Financial Documents, 1966-1972 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - MUCIA Guidelines for Submitting Requests for Financial Support, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Assorted Correspondence About CIS Finances, 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Assorted Correspondence About CIS Finances, 1966-1967 (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - Sales Tax Forms, February 1973-Septemeber 1974 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Assorted Papers, Fall 1979 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - RDPP, November 1979 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Assorted Papers, December 1979 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - U20-8372 Operating Statements, Rural Development Part. Prog., January 1980 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - RDPP, February 1980 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Assorted Papers, March 1980 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Assorted Papers, Spring 1980 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - U20-8372 Unpaid Bills Rural Development Part. Prog., June 1980 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Assorted Papers, Summer 1970 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - RDPP 8372, August 1980 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - U20-8372, September 1980 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - RDPP September-October 1980 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Assorted Papers, November 1980 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Assorted Papers, December 1980 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Assorted Papers, January 1981 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - U20-8372, February 1981 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Monthly Payroll Register, June-September 1981 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - U20-8372 Monthly Forms - Rural Development Part. Program (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Salary Recovery RDPP, 1978-1981 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Assorted Papers, Late Summer to Fall 1980 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Unpaid Bills: U20-8372 Rural Development Participation Program, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Assorted Papers, July-November 1979 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Assorted Papers, March 1981 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Assorted Papers, September 1981 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Assorted Papers, April 1981 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Assorted Papers, May 1981 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Endowed Colleges: Accounts Payable Standard Information Sheets, June 1981 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Series II. Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory
  - Newspaper Article Explaining Cornell's Issues with CAL, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - CAL - Confidential, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Documents Concerning CAL, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Ithaca Journal Article About CAL, July 6, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Concerning CAL, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, March 1967-September 1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - CAL Documents regarding CAL's Involvement with Thailand, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - CAL Documents, October 1967-January 1968 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Series III. CIS and Related Publications
  - "The Air War in Indochina"
    - Manuscript for "The Air War in Indochina", August 1972 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Review of "The Air War in Indochina" in the "New York Times Book Review", August 13, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Review of "The Air War in Indochina," in "Beacon Press"2, Fall 1972 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Assorted Publicity for "The Air War in Indochina", 1972 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - "Air War in Indochina" from "Intellectual Digest" (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Mail Orders from "The Air War in Indochina", 1972 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Checks and Order Forms for "The Air War in Indochina", 1972-1973 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Papers and Mailing Lists Related to "The Air War in Indochina," 1970s, 1970s (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - "The Air War in Indochina" Rough Papers (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - "The Air War in Indochina": Draft (Box 12)
    - "The Air War in Indochina": Draft 2 (Box 12)
    - "The Air War in Indochina": Draft 3 (Box 12)
  - CIS Newsletter, Possibly for Staff, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - CIS International Studies Bulletin, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - CIS International Studies Bulletin, September 1968-November 1968 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Publications: Newsletter Production Info, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Publications: Newsletter Production Info, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Publications: Newsletter Production Info, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Publications: Newsletter Production Info, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - International Studies Newsletter, Volume 5 Number 1, November 1973 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - University of Pittsburgh International Newsletter, January 1975 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - International Studies Newsletter, Volume 6 Number 1, Spring 1975 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - University of Minnesota International Programs Newsletter, Vol. 01, No. 4, June 1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Some Reflections on the International Monetary Reform and Europe's Independence and Regional Identity," by Jaroslav Vanak, November 1972 (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - Regionalism in North West England, 1964-1974, by Pierre Clavel (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "Trade Unions and Women in the Labor Market and in Political Life: A Comparative Study of Union Policies and Programs in Seven Western Societies" (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Assorted University Publications, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Assorted CIS Essays and Related Documents (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Series IV. Fellowships, Grants, Foundations, and Institutions
  - ESC-Ford
    - ESC-East Europe, March 1967- October 1968 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - ESC-Ford, 1967-1968 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - ESC-Exchange Progs. Louvain University, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - ESC-Ford, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - ESC Ford Grant and letter prop., 1970 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - ESC-Ford 700-0535, 1970-1971 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - European Studies Program, March 1971-February 1973 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - ESC-Ford 700-0535, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - ESC Ford Grant, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - ESC Calls to Mtgs., 1965-1967 (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - ESC Calls to Mtgs., 1965-1967 (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Assorted Proposals for the European Studies Commission, 1968-1973 (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - European Studies Committee Papers, March 1970-1973 (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - Assorted European Studies Committee Documents, 1970s (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - European Studies Steering Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 14, Folder 41)
    - European Studies Committee Activities, 1972-1973 (Box 14, Folder 42)
    - ESC Grants General, 1970-1973 (Box 14, Folder 43)
    - ESC Ford 700-0535, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 44)
    - Recipients ESC Grants, April 1973 (Box 14, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence-ESC Grants, April 1973 (Box 14, Folder 46)
    - ESC-Small Grants, Rejections (Proposals), April 1973 (Box 14, Folder 47)
    - Faculty Activities (Box 14, Folder 48)
    - Staff ESC Alphabetical (Box 14, Folder 49)
    - Worksheets--Center for European Studies (Box 14, Folder 50)
    - ESC-1954 Mtgs. (Box 18, Folder 94)
  - Fulbright Hays
    - Fulbright Hays 1971-1972, Papers from 1969 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Fulbright Hays Richard Ivry, 1971-1972 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Fulbright Hays, 1972-1973 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Fulbright Hays Analysis Sheets, January-June 1973 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Fulbright Hays, 1973-1974 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Fulbright Hays Intl. Visitors/Lecturers Exchange, 1970s (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Fulbright Hays Admin. (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Douglas Ashford Ford Fellowship Correspondence, February 1963-May 1963 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Documents Addressing CIS Fellowships, 1963-1970 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Documents Concerning Ford Foundation Grant, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "A Request for Long-Range Support by Cornell University to the Ford Foundation", 1966 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Ford Foundation Correspondence Bestowing Grant, April 14, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Papers on CIS Grant Requests, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Aid Institutional (Sec.211) Grant Documents, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Papers and Correspondence about the Ford Foundation Grant, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Further Correspondence Concerning Grants for European Studies, 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Report on Activities for 1971-1972 Under Grant No. 70-535, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Fourth Annual Report to the Ford Foundation on the Grant to Cornell University for Graduate Training and Research in Non-Western and Other International Studies, September 1966 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - University Committees: Research Grants Committee, April 7, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Study Fellowships for International Development, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 06A)
  - Study Fellowships for International Development, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 06B)
  - Phase II Area and Related International Studies Centers Receiving USOE Grants, 1974-1975 and 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Foreign Languages and Area Studies: Instructions for Application for Federal Assistance, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Comprehensive On-Site Review of 211(d) Grant to Cornell University on Policies for Science and Technology in Developing Nations, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Assorted Fellowship Papers, Mainly International Development, 1963-1967 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Assorted Fellowship Correspondence, Mainly International Development, 1965-1966 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Advertisement for International Development Fellowship, 1967-1968 (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence Concerning Women's Studies Program's Finance, July-October 1972 (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - Progress Report on Women's Studies Activities, December 14, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - "Some Aspects of Technical Assistance: An Unorthodox Indian View," by Ray Krishna; Part of an Application for International Development Fellowship, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - "Program on International Nutrition and Development Policy," Draft Proposal and Related Papers, Fall 1972 (Box 10, Folder 63)
  - Interview Forms for International Development Fellowship, March 3, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 71)
  - Course Paperwork and Related Fellowship Details for Chandler Morse, Spring 1966 (Box 10, Folder 72)
  - Assorted Notes on Fellowships, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 73)
  - Assorted Correspondence, Mainly About Fulbright Applications, 1969-1977 (Box 10, Folder 75)
  - U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare Amendment of Grant Agreement, June 25, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 76)
  - "A Proposal for Assistance to Develop a Two-Term Graduate Seminar in the Theory and Practice of Overseas Development," for International Development Fellowship, April 1, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - "Trade Liberalization and Economic Development in Latin America (1750-1850), Fulbright-Harp Proposal by Tom Edward Davis, June 11, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - "Preparation of a Cebuano-English Dictionary," Fulbright-Hays Fellowship Proposal by John Ulrich Wolff, November 1, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - "Compilation of Intermediate Reading: Materials in the Vietnam Language," Fulbright-Hays Fellowship Application by Robert M. Quinn, September 10, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 86)
  - Faculty Research Grants Committee, Cornell University: Statement of Policy and Procedure (Box 10, Folder 93)
  - Papers on International Fellowship Meeting, April 2-4, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 100)
  - "Study Fellowships for International Development Meeting", March 18-20, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 102)
  - CIS Fellows-Nominations, October-December 1969 (Box 10, Folder 103)
  - Papers About United Nations Intern Program, 1972-1975 (Box 10, Folder 105)
  - Information on Internship in Section on Prevention of Discrimination and Protection of Minorities, Division of Human Rights, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 107)
  - Brenda G. Plummer: Compton Fellowship Application, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Linda Lacey: Compton Fellowship Application, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Mercedes Lopez-Baralt: Compton Fellowship Application, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Compton Applications, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Compton Fellowships, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Marshall Fund Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Ford Foundation: INT'L Economic Order, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Foundations: Ford Correspondence, Early-Mid 1970s (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Rockefeller and Ford Foundation Papers (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Institute of International Education, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - National Science Foundation, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - The Lehrman Institute, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Donner Foundation, December 9, 1974, December 9, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Foundations: Einaudi, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - S.A.I.S. Washington Ctr. of For. Policy Research, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Foundations: Other, mid 1970s (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Foundations: Marshall, mid 1970s (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - International Studies Assoc., mid 1970s (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Foreign Area Fellowship Program, Fall 1972, Fall 1972 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Swedish Kennedy Scholarship, December 1974, December 1974 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - American Council of Learned Societies Applications, 1975-1976 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Fellowships, national and International, mid-1970s (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Deutsche Forschungs-Gemeinschaft (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Grant Applications External, 1970s (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Grant Application Material: "New Modes of Participation" Nelkin et al., 1973 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Standford's Interdisciplinary Undergraduate Program in International Relations; "A Proposal to the National Endowment for the Humanities for a Five Year-Development Grant", April 16, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - "The Rockefeller Foundation: Staff and Program News", June 30, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 69)
  - "Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars: Fellowship and Guest Scholar Programs", 1973 (Box 18, Folder 70)
- Series V. Faculty and Visitor Related Documents
  - Irwin T. Sanders Evaluations
    - Irwin T. Sanders Evaluation: Correspondence-Inter-departmental, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - International Programs at Cornell University: Observations and Recommendations," by Irwin T. Sanders, April 15, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - China Program: Annual Report by Irwin T. Sanders, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Papers on Irwin T. Sanders' Visits to Cornell, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Correspondence and Papers Related to Irwin T. Sanders, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Latin American Studies: Report for Irwin T. Sanders, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - International Legal Studies: Sander's Visit, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Irwin T. Sanders Evaluation: Meetings, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Irwin T. Sanders Evaluation: Correspondence, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Structural Change and Modernization also C.E.D. (Comparative Economic Development): Annual Report, Irwin Sanders, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - London-Cornell Project: Irwin T. Sanders-General, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - "International Programs at Cornell University: Observations and Recommendations," Irwin T. Sanders, April 15, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 89)
  - Assorted Correspondence Concerning CIS Visiting Professors, 1963-1970 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Assorted Correspondence Concerning CIS Visiting Professors, 1966-1970 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence Concerning Acquiring Visitors, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Papers Relating to Vladimir Dedizer, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Papers from Scott Adam's Visit, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - Martha Wallace's Visit (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Tax and Visa Information Foreign Visitors, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Curriculum Vitae for Yussuf Naim Kly, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence About Adrian Sinfield of University of Essex as a Visiting Scholar, November 18, 1977-May 8, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - ILF: Professor V. Jensen, Associate Dean, Frank Stevens, Visitor (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Assorted Papers Discussing International Law Program's Financial Affairs, 1962-1975 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Nomination of James Green for a Position Through CIS, February 23, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Conversation About Bringing John V. Muria to Cornell, March 7, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Clark Foundation, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Kellogg, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Papers on Visiting Professors, October 1967 (Box 10, Folder 87)
  - Papers on Monetary Awards for Faculty, 1969-1970 (Box 10, Folder 88)
  - Documentation About Upcoming Lectures and Visitor Presentations, 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 90)
  - Curriculum Vitae of Moonis Raza, October 14, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 91)
  - Curriculum Vitae of Ved P. Kayastha, Stanley J. O'Connor, Kenneth A.R. Kennedy (Box 10, Folder 92)
  - "A Declaration by Cornell Faculty Members", April 27, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - George Quester: Activities and Correspondence, 1970-1976 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence Concerning Judy Reppy, 1974-1976 (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Uma Lele - Curriculum Vitae (Box 18, Folder 32)
- Series VI. CIS Committees and Affairs
  - CIS Executive Committee Documents, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - CIS Executive Committee Documents, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - CIS Committees, Appointments Committee (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - CIS Committees, Evaluation Committee, 1964-1969 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - CIS Evaluation Committee Documents, September 1967-November 1968 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Resumes from Applicants for CIS Director Position, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Memorandum for Suggestions for the Directorship of CIS, December 28, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Center Appointment Committee Documents Concerning Choosing a New Director, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - CIS Directors Committee Documents Concerning Hiring a New Director, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Minutes of the CIS Evaluation Committee, September 1968-December 1969 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Assorted Evaluation Committee Correspondence and Documents, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - CIS Evaluation Committee Documents, December 1968-December 1969 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Summary of the Preliminary Recommendations of the CIS Evaluation Committee, January 1969 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - CIS Committees Overseas Committee, 1964-1969 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - CIS Executive Committee Documents, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Faculty Appointments by Centers, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Guideline: Center for International Studies, November 16, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Members 1961 to Present, 1961-1970 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Executive Committee Reorganization, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Executive Committee Reorganization, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Executive Committee Membership Correspondence pre 1970-71, 1964-1969 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Executive Committee Membership Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Executive Committee Membership Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Executive Committee Membership Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - "Draft Memorandum for Review of CIS Executive Committee and Area Program Directors", February 12, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Executive Committee Meetings, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Executive Committee Membership Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - "Organization and Functions: Center for International Studies" (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - CIS Logistical Documents, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - 1969 Executive Committee Evaluation of CIS, March 27, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - CIS Executive Committee Meeting, April 30, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - CIS Documents About Inter-Institutional Cooperation, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - CIS Space Renovation Estimates, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - "Draft Memorandum for Review of CIS Executive Committee and Area Program Directors", February 12, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Committee on the Future of International Studies Papers, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - CIS Organization and History Chronology, 1961-1962 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - CIS Organization and History, Chronological, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - CIS Organization and History, Chronological, 1965-1967 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - CIS Organization and History, Chronological, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - CIS Records Survey, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - CIS Organization and History, Chronological, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - CIS Organization and History, Chronological, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - CIS Organization and History, Chronological (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Assorted Documents of CIS Undergraduate Program, 1968-1972 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - CIS-General Documents, 1963-1970 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Minutes of the CIS Evaluation Committee Meeting of December 27, 1968, December 27, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 44)